以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以这是数学上的重要日子
so this is a big day mathematically
说话，因为我们来到这个关键
speaking because we come to this key
想法是像一点点
idea which is a little bit like
特征值很像特征值
eigenvalues well a lot like eigenvalues
但因为矩阵现在不同了
but different because the matrix a now
通常是矩形的，所以对于a
is more usually rectangular so for a
矩形矩阵的整体思想
rectangular matrix the whole idea of
特征值是因为如果我
eigenvalues is shot because if I
乘以n中的向量X的次数
multiply a times a vector X in n
后尺寸出将并购来的东西
dimensions out will come something in M
尺寸，它不会相等
dimensions and it's not going to equal
lambdaX所以ax等于lambdaX不是
lambda X so ax equal lambda X is not
甚至可能
even possible
如果a是矩形，即使a是
if a is rectangular and even if a is
方块有什么问题
square what are the problems just
思考一下特征值
thinking for a minute about eigenvalues
我在这里写的案例是
the the case I wrote up here is the
我有一个对称的大案例
great case where I have a symmetric
矩阵，然后它有一整套
matrix and then it's got a full set of
特征值和特征向量，它们是
eigenvalues and eigenvectors and they're
正交一切都好，但对于一般
orthogonal all good but for a general
方阵矩阵或特征向量
square matrix either the eigenvectors
复杂的特征值是复杂的还是复杂的
are complex eigenvalues are complex or
特征向量不是正交的
the eigen vectors are not orthogonal so
所以我们不能保持特征值
so we we can't stay with eigenvalues
永远这就是我说的和这个
forever that's what I'm saying and this
是这样做是正确的做法
is the right thing to do a is know so
这些是什么，所以这些是
what are these pieces so these are the
左，这些是正确的单数
left and these are the right singular
向量所以这就是新词
vectors so this is the the new word is
单数
singular
而在之间去的不是
and in between go the not the
特征值，但奇异值，所以
eigenvalues but singular values so that
所以我们现在已经掌握了重点
so we've gotten the whole point now you
得到了这有两套
got pick up on this there are two sets
奇异向量不是一个
of singular vectors not one for
我们只有一个设置的特征向量
eigenvectors we just had one set the
队列现在我们有矩形
queues now we have for rectangular
矩阵我们有一组左
matrix we've got one set of left
m维和特征中的特征向量
eigenvectors in in m dimensions and
我们有另一套权利
we've got another set of right
n维和数字的特征向量
eigenvectors in n dimensions and numbers
中间不是图标值而是
in between are not icon values but
奇异的价值所以这些家伙让我
singular values so these guys are let me
写下看起来像这样的东西
write what that looks like this is again
对角矩阵说我的两个西格玛
a diagonal matrix say my two two sigma
或者让我们说这又是一个对角线
or let's say so it's again a diagonal
中间的矩阵，但数字
matrix in the middle but the numbers on
对角线都是正数或0和
the diagonal are all positive or 0 and
它们被称为奇异值，所以它是
they're called singular values so it's
只是一个不同的世界真的很好
just a different world okay so really
第一步，我必须做数学题
the first step i have to do the math
步骤是表明任何矩阵都可以
step is to show that any matrix has can
被考虑到你的西格玛时代V
be factored into u times sigma times V
转不过就是这样这就是
transpose so that's that that's the
平行于光谱定理
parallel to the spectral theorem that
可以考虑任何对称矩阵
any symmetric matrix could be factored
那样你对那部分有好处
that way so you're good for that part
我们必须要做到这一点
we'll have to we just have to do it to
看你是什么，Sigma和V是什么
see what are you and Sigma and V what
是那些向量和那些单数
are those vectors and those singular
值得好，让我们走吧所以关键是
values okay let's go so the key is that
转置a是一个很好的矩阵
a transpose a is a great matrix so
这是这是关键的关键
that's the key that's the key to the
数学是一转的一所以一
math is a transpose a so one of the
转置的属性a
properties of a transpose a
这是一个矩形，所以也许
this is a is rectangular again so maybe
m-by-natranspose就是这样的
m-by-n a transpose is so this was em by
这是由M得到的，所以我们得到一个结果
n this was n by M so we get a result
这是n和你能告诉你还有什么
that's n by n and what else can you tell
关于转置这个是一件大事
me about a transpose a that's a big deal
这是正方形的，是的，你可以
and it's square and well yeah you can
现在告诉我更多因为我们谈过
tell me more now because we talked about
这是一个有话题的话题
something a topic that's there's a
它比上次对称还要多
little more than symmetric last time it
矩阵a转置a将
the matrix a transpose a will be
肯定的是它的特征值是
positive definite its eigenvalues are
大于或等于零，这将意味着
greater or equal zero and that will mean
我们可以采取他们的平方根和
that we can take their square roots and
这就是我们将要做的事情
that's what we will do so a transpose a
会有一个因子化，它是对称的
will have a factorization it's symmetric
它会像QlambdaQ转置一样
it'll have a like a Q lambda Q transpose
但我会称之为Vlambdanoyesaha
but I'm gonna call it V lambda no yeah a
lambda我仍称它为lambdaV.
lambda I'll still call it lambda V
颠倒
transpose
所以这些V是我们对此的了解
so these V's what do we know about the
特征向量所以这些费用或
eigenvectors so these fees or
这个家伙的特征向量
eigenvectors of this guy square
对称正定矩阵
symmetric positive-definite matrix so
我们处于良好的状态，我们知道什么
we're in good shape and what do we know
关于转置的特征值
about the eigenvalues of of a transpose
他们都是积极的，所以
a they are all positive so the
特征值恰好等于0和0
eigenvalues are well or equal to 0 and
这些人是正交的，这些家伙
these guys are orthogonal and these guys
在那里更加平等，好吧
are greater equal there and okay so
那是好的，这是我们的一个
that's good that's one of our that's a
很大程度上取决于你，但也取决于你
will depend a lot on that but also you
我认识到aatranspose是一个
got to recognize that a a transpose is a
不同的家伙aatranspose所以
different different guy a a transpose so
所以什么什么是一个一个的形状
so what what's the shape of a a
转换我现在有多大
transpose how big is that now I've got
我在哪里得到M乘以n乘以N乘以M.
where do I have M by n times n by M so
这将是M与M不同的大小
this will be what size M by M different
形状
shape
但具有相同的特征值相同
but with the same eigenvalues the same
特征值所以它会有一些
eigenvalue so it's going to have some
其他特征向量你当然是我
other eigenvectors you of course I'm
打算叫你，因为我会
going to call them you because I gonna
去那边，他们会一样的
go in over there they'll be the same
好吧，他们说是的，我的意思是不，我
well they're saying yeah I mean no I
不应该，我不得不说，当我说的
shouldn't I have to say when I say the
同样的，我不能毫不夸张意味
same I can't quite literally mean the
非常相同，因为这有n
very same because this has got n
特征值，这已经有了
eigenvalues and this has got em
特征值，但失踪的家伙
eigenvalues but the the the missing guys
在那些身在其中的一个不
the ones that are in one of them not on
另取决于大小
the other depending on the sizes are
零真的是事情的核心
zeros so really the heart of the thing
非零特征值是相同的
that nonzero eigenvalues are the same
好吧，现在我实际上已经很好了
okay now well actually I've pretty much
揭示了SVD将要使用的内容
revealed what the SVD is going to use
它会使用使用从这里
it's going to use the use from here and
在V从这儿但是这是这样的
the V's from here but that's that's the
故事，你必须看到这个故事好吗
story you've got to see that story okay
如此新鲜的奇异价值开始
so fresh start on the singular value
分解我们在寻找什么
decomposition what are we looking for
以及我们正在寻找的分解因素
well as a factorization so we're looking
对于
for
我们想要一个我们想要的矢量V这样的时候
we want a we want vectors V so that when
我乘以V，如果它是一个本征
I multiply by V so if it was an eigen
矢量它将是V等于λV
vector it would be a V equal lambda V
但现在它的长方形不是
but now for a it's rectangular it's not
你没有Argan因素所以AV是
you hasn't got Argan factors so AV is
西格玛新的我奇异值乘以你
Sigma the new I singular value times u
这是第一个人和第二个人
that's the first guy and the second guy
和ARESCAG我会在停止是
and the are scag I'll stop at are the
排名是的
rank yeah
是什么我买嘿让我
is that what I bought hey let me just
看到AV是西格玛，你是的，这很好
see AV is Sigma you yeah that's good
好的，这就是取而代之的
okay so this is what takes the place of
斧等于拉姆达XA的一组次
ax equal lambda X a times one set of
奇异向量给了我很多次
singular vectors gives me a number times
另一组奇异向量和
the other set of singular vectors and
我为什么停下来是因为
why did I stop at are the rank because
在此之后，适马是0，所以后
after that the Sigma's are 0 so after
我可以有更多的家伙但是
that I could have some more guys but
它们将在零空间0中
they'll be in the null space 0 on down
VN所以这些是重要的
to of VN so these are the important ones
这就是我在寻找的东西
so that's what I'm looking for
我可以卖掉让我现在用语言说出来
can I sell let me say it now in words
我正在寻找一堆正交
I'm looking for a bunch of orthogonal
向量V，以便当我乘以它们时
vectors V so that when I multiply them
通过我得到一堆正交向量
by a I get a bunch of orthogonal vectors
你不是那么清楚，但它
u that is not so clearly possible but it
它有可能它确实发生我
it it is possible it does happen I'm
寻找一组正交
looking for one set of orthogonal
矢量V在输入空间中你可以
vectors V in the input space you could
这样说就是输出中的一个V'
say so that the a V's in the output
在我们的图片中，空间也正交
space are also orthogonal in our picture
你知道我们的图片
of you know our picture of the
基本的大局
fundamental the the big picture of
线性代数我们在这里有这些
linear algebra we have these in this
空格，然后在零空间中的东西
space and then stuff in the null space
我们在这里有看法
and we have views over here in the
列空间和null中的一些东西
column space and some stuff in the null
在那边的空间，我的想法是
space over there and the idea is that I
这里有正交的V和我
have orthogonal V's here and when I
乘以a乘以a然后我
multiply by a so multiplied by a then I
在这里正交使用正交
get orthogonal use over here orthogonal
正交就是这就是什么
to orthogonal that's what that's what
使V和他们使用
makes the V's and they use
特别的权利没关系就是那个
special right okay that's that's the
财产，然后当我们写下来
property and then when we write down
好吧，让我写下那会是什么
well let me write down what that would
这意味着我刚画了一张照片
mean what so I've just drawn a picture
顺其那些方程式
to go with this those equations that
图片与这些方程式一致
picture just goes with these equations
让我写下它意味着什么
and let me just write down what it means
它意味着矩阵所以我写了哦
it means in matrix so I've written it oh
是的我在这里用矢量一写了
yeah I've written it here in vectors one
在一个时间，但当然你知道我
at a time but of course you know I'm
将这些矢量放入列中
gonna put those vectors into the columns
一个矩阵，所以v1倍于let的
of a matrix so a times v1 up to let's
说VR会等于哦是的等于
say V R will equal oh yeah it equals
西格玛时代使用所以这就是我的意思
Sigma times use so this is what I'm
之后是u1直到你乘以
after is u1 up to you are multiplied by
西格玛一个属于西格玛，我是什么
Sigma one belong to Sigma ha what I'm
现在做的只是说我正在转变
doing now is just to say I'm converting
这些单独的奇异向量各V
these individual singular vectors each V
进入au把它们全部放进去
going into au to putting them all
当然，我们一起进入矩阵
together into a matrix and of course
我在这里写的是V等于你
what I've written here is a V equals u
SigmaaV等于uSigma就是这样
Sigma a V equals u Sigma that's what
这相当于我要放
that amounts to well then I'm gonna put
一个V转置在这一边，我会
a V transpose on this side and I'm gonna
得到一个等于你的西格玛V转置
get to a equals u Sigma V transpose
将两边乘以V
multiplying both sides there by V
转置你我有点写同样的东西
transpose u I'm kind of writing the same
不同形式矩阵形式的东西
thing in different forms matrix form
矢量在时间形式，现在我们必须
vector at a time form and now we have to
现在找到他们我已经用完了
find them now now I've used up boards
说出我们所追求的，但现在我们得到了
saying what we're after but now we got
到达那里什么是V和
to get there so what are the V's and
有什么用？
what are the use
好的想法是想到一个
well the cool idea is to think of a
转移一个所以你和我在一起我们是什么
transpose a so you're with me what we're
对于现在想想转置一个这样
for and now think about a transpose a so
我，如果这是我希望的
I if this is what I'm hoping for
什么会转一个练得
what will a transpose a turn out to be
如此重要的时刻即将揭示
so big moment that's going to reveal
如果我形成一个，那么v是什么
what the v's are so if I form a
转置一个这样的转置，所以我有一个
transpose a so a transpose so I've got a
转移这个家伙所以转置是V
transpose this guy so a transpose is V
Sigma转换你的转置权利和
Sigma transpose u transpose right and
然后是一个这是你的西格玛V
then comes a which is this u Sigma V
转置，为什么我这样做
transpose so why did I do that
为什么转置a很酷
why is it that a transpose a is the cool
要看问题来解决问题
thing to look at to make the problem
什么使得变成什么更简单
simpler well what what make what becomes
在那条线上写的比较简单
simpler in that line just written u
转置你是我的身份因为我
transpose u is the identity because I'm
实际上寻找正交
looking for orthogonal in fact
正交使用，这是身份
orthonormal use so that's the identity
所以这是VSigma转换SigmaV
so this is V Sigma transpose Sigma V
转置将流程围绕在那里
transpose put processes around that
因为这是一个对角矩阵没关系
because that's a diagonal matrix okay
那是什么告诉我这是什么呢
what does that tell me what does that
告诉我们所有人一个转置a有这个
tell all of us a transpose a has this
窗体现在我们已经看到了我们之前的形式
form now we've seen that form before we
知道这是一个对称矩阵
know that this is a symmetric matrix
对称甚至是正定的
symmetric and even positive definite so
什么是V的V是本征
what are the V's the V's are the eigen
转置的向量在这里
vectors of a transpose a here where this
这是QlambdaQ的转置
is the Q lambda Q transpose for that
对称矩阵所以我们知道v是
symmetric matrix so we know the v's are
特征向量
the eigenvectors the
转置a和I的特征向量
the eigen vectors of a transpose a and I
我猜我们也会去那里
guess we're also going to get there the
奇异值使Sigma转换
singular value so the Sigma transpose
Sigma将成为SigmaSquared的
Sigma which will be the Sigma Squared's
是转置的特征值a
are the eigenvalues of a transpose a
好样的通过寻找正确的
good sort of by looking for the correct
事情你西格玛V转置然后
thing you Sigma V transpose and then
只是使用你转移你的邪恶
just using the u transpose u evil
身份我们把它回到我们的东西
identity we cut it back to something we
我们完全认识到一个转置
we perfectly recognize a transpose a has
那形成所以现在我们知道V是什么
that form so now we know what the V's
是，如果我做的其他方式，其
are and if I do it the other way which
有什么其他的方式，而不是
what's the other way instead of a
转移另一种方式是，如果我
transpose a the other way is and if I
写下所有那些是你的西格玛
write all that down the a is the u Sigma
V转置和转置是V
V transpose and the a transpose is the V
Sigma转换你的转置和再次
Sigma transpose u transpose and again
这东西消失了，离开了我
this stuff goes away and leaves me with
你SigmaSigmaSigma转换你
you Sigma Sigma Sigma transpose u
转置所以我知道要使用的是-
transpose so I know what to use are -
它们是转移的特征向量
they're the eigenvectors of a a transfer
你不是那种美丽的对称
isn't that a beautiful symmetry you just
a转置a和aa转置他们是
a transpose a and a a transpose they're
两个不同的家伙现在所以他们各自
two different guys now so they have each
有自己的特征向量，我们都使用它们
has its own eigenvectors and we use both
它是正确的，我只需要采取
it's just right and i just have to take
最后一步，我们已经确立了
the final step and and we've established
SVD所以最后一步是要记住
the SVD so the final step is to remember
我要去的地方有一次V是
what I'm going for here a times a V is
应该是西格玛时代的你
supposed to be Sigma times a you
看看我有什么需要处理的
see what I'm what I have to deal with
现在我还没有完成它
now is I haven't quite finished it's
尽管如此，它还是完美无缺的
it's just perfect as far as it goes but
它还没有走到尽头，因为我们
it hasn't gone to the end yet because we
可以有双特征值和三倍
could have double eigenvalues and triple
特征值和所有那些可怕的
eigenvalues and all those horrible
可能性，如果我有三倍
possibilities and if i have triple
然后是特征值或双特征值
eigenvalues or double eigenvalues then
如果我有什么特征向量的交易
what's the deal with eigenvectors if i
具有双特征值假设矩阵
have double eigenvalue suppose a matrix
有一种类型说对称矩阵有一个
has a type say a symmetric matrix has a
双特征值让我只需要一个
double eigenvalue let me just take an
例如对称矩阵如111
example so symmetric matrix like say 1 1
5让它为什么不能有什么处理
5 make it why not what's the deal with
该矩阵的特征向量115所以5
eigenvectors for that matrix 1 1 5 so 5
有一个特征向量你可以看到什么
has got an eigenvector you can see what
它是00有关的特征向量1什么
it is 0 0 1 what about the eigenvectors
为此，lambda等于1
that go with lambda equal 1 for that
矩阵怎么了我将会是什么
matrix what's up what I what would be
lambda的特征向量等于1
eigenvectors for lambda equal 1
不幸的是，有一整个平面
unfortunately there's a whole plane of
他们任何形式的矢量
them any vector of the full of the form
XY0XY平面中的任何任何矢量
XY 0 any any any vector in the XY plane
会产生XY0
would produce XY 0
特征向量的旅行平面，我
travel plane of eigenvectors and i've
有一个选择两个是正交的这
got a pick two that are orthogonal which
我能做到，然后他们必须在
i can do and then they have to be in the
在SVD中是两个正交的人
in the SVD that was two orthogonal guys
一定要到两个正交的家伙
have to go to two orthogonal guys in
换句话说有点像
other words is a little bit of like
细节在这里很少进入这个
detail here little getting into this
究竟什么才能让我放过
exactly what is well actually let me let
我告诉你步骤好，所以我用它
me tell you the steps ok so I use this
得出结论认为v是
to conclude that that the v's the
奇异向量应该被电离I
singular vector should be ionized I
结束了这一步的人
concluded those guys from this step
现在我不会那么多地使用这一步
now I'm not gonna use this step so much
当然，这是我的想法
of course it's in the back of my mind
但是我没有使用它我会得到它
but I'm not using it I I'm gonna get the
从这里使用，所以你是一个V1结束
use from here so you one is a V 1 over
西格玛1就是西格玛的VR
Sigma 1 the you are is a V R over Sigma
R请勿你看到我在这里做
R do you see what I'm doing here
我正在挑选一架可能的飞机
I'm picking in a possible plane of
我希望他们使用的东西我想要的
things the one I want they use I want so
我选择了V，我选择了
I've chosen the V's I've chosen the
西格玛，他们是固定的
Sigma's they were they're fixed for a
转置特征向量RV的
transpose a the eigenvectors RV's the
这个特征值是西格玛
things this eigen values are Sigma
平方的还好，现在则是这样的
Squared's okay and now then this is the
UI想要你和我在一起，所以我不得不这样做
U I want are you with me so I had to I
不得不给我想要得到这些用途
had to give I want to get these use
正确的，如果我有一个完整的飞机
correct and if I have a whole plane of
我必须选择正确的可能性
possibilities I got to pick the right
一个好的，现在我终于要表现出来了
one okay and now finally I have to show
这是正确的，所以还剩下什么
that it's the right one so what is left
表明我会证明这些用途是
to show I would show that these use are
转置的特征向量和i
eigenvectors of a a transpose and i
应该表明它们是正交的
should show that they're orthogonal
对，这是关键的权利ii会
right that's the key right i i would
喜欢表明这些是正交的
like to show that these are orthogonal
那就是这张照片中的内容
then that's what goes in this picture
v我是正统的伙伴因为
the v's I've got orthogonal guys because
我他们是他们的特征向量
I they're they're the eigenvectors of a
对称矩阵选择更彻底
symmetric matrix pick a more thorough
但是现在我正在增加一个，所以我
but now I'm multiplying by a so I'm
得到U的AV是超过Sigma的
getting the U which is AV over Sigma for
基础向量和我必须表明
the basis vectors and I have to show
他们是正交的
they're orthogonal
所以这就像最后一刻一样
so this is like the final moment does
如果我，一切都在一起
everything come together right if I
选择V作为a的特征向量
picked the V's as the eigen vectors of a
颠倒
transpose
然后我把这些用于使用
and then I take these for the use are
他们正交，所以我想
they orthogonal so I would like to think
我们可以检查那个事实
that we can check that fact and it that
它会好的，你可以吗？
it will come out okay could you just
通过这个帮助我，我永远不会问
help me through this one I'll never ask
只是为了得到任何东西
for anything again just just just get
SVD还好，所以我想展示一下
the SVD for okay so I would like to show
那个让你放弃的那个
that a that you one that's so let me put
我正在做的事情我想表现出来
up what I'm doing I'm trying to show
u1转置u2为零
that u 1 transpose u 2 is zero
有可溶性好，所以你1是V1
there are soluble okay so u 1 is a V 1
超过西格玛1
over Sigma 1
那是你的转换你和你是一个
that's transpose that's u 1 and u 2 is a
在Sigma2V2，我希望得到0
V 2 over Sigma 2 and I want to get 0 the
整个谈话已经结束了
whole conversation has ended right is
在这里结束为什么这个改变0
ending right here why is that change 0
V是正交的
the V's are orthogonal
我们知道签证正交有
we know the visa orthogonal there are
saga正常的转置特征向量
saga normal eigen vectors of a transpose
a要重复V是的
a to be repeat that the V's are
转置的正交特征向量
orthogonal eigen vectors of a transpose
我知道他们在那里我们
a which I know they're there there we
可以找到他们然后我选择使用
can find them then I chose the use to be
这个，我想得到的答案是0
this and I want to get the answer 0 are
你准备好做它，我们希望我们要
you ready to do it we want to we want to
计算并得到0所以我得到了什么
compute that and get 0 so what do I get
我们只需要这样做就可以看到了
let's we just have to do it so I can see
分母就是那样的V.
that the denominator is that so is it V
1转置右转AV2
1 transpose a transpose right times AV 2
我希望得到零，我得零
and I'm hoping to get zero do I get zero
这里
here
你希望所以是的v1是正交v2但是
you hope so yeah v1 is orthogonal v2 but
我有一个插入棍子的转置
I've got a transpose a stick stuck in
中间那里我该怎么做
the middle there so what do I what
发生在这里我怎么看待v2是
happens here how do I look at that v2 is
转置的特征向量是一个了不起的
an eigenvector of a transpose a terrific
所以这是V1转置，这是
so so this is V 1 transpose and this is
矩阵乘以V2，使得Sigma2
the matrix times V 2 so that's Sigma 2
转置V2不是它
transpose V 2 isn't it
它是具有特征值的特征向量
it's the eigenvector with eigenvalue
Sigma2平方乘以V2yep除以
Sigma 2 squared times V 2 yep divided by
西格玛1西格玛2所以A的出局
Sigma 1 Sigma 2 so the A's are out of
我现在就这样做，所以我只是削减
there now and do I so I've just cuts
这些数字西格玛2平方所以
these numbers Sigma 2 squared so that
我会是Sigma2而不是Sigma1
would be Sigma 2 over Sigma 1 is I've
这里的数字占这些数字的时间
accounted for these numbers here times V
1转V2，现在什么事有
1 transpose V 2 and now what's up there
正交我们得到它的0是0
orthonormal we got it that's 0 that is 0
是的，所以不仅是V的
there yeah so so not only are the V's
彼此正交，但因为
orthogonal to each other but because
他们是转换的RIghen向量a
they're RI ghen vectors of a transpose a
当我这样做时，我发现了一个V的
when I do this I discover that the a V's
超过在相互正交
are orthogonal to each other over in the
在列空间中正交Vin
in the column space so orthogonal V's in
行空间正交AVsover
the row space orthogonal AV s over in
发现的列空间
the column space that was discovered
在特征向量和特征向量之后很久很久
late much long after eigenvectors and
这是一段有趣的历史
it's a interesting history
它只是出来然后它
and it just comes out right and then it
被发现，但没有太多用于哦
was discovered but not much used for Oh
可能是一百年
a hundred years probably
然后人们看到它确切地说
and then people saw that it was exactly
正确的事情，数据矩阵成为
the right thing and data matrices became
重要的是大矩形
important which are large rectangular
矩阵，我们没有哦，我更好地说
matrices and we have not oh I better say
实际上，这里只是一个词
a word just a word here about actually
计算v和Sigma和
computing the v's and the Sigma's and
他们如此使用你会如何找到
they use so how would you actually find
他们，你最想说的就是你
them you what I most want to say is you
不会为了这个转置根本为什么
would not go this a transpose a root why
为什么这是一个大错误
why is it like it is that a big mistake
如果你有一个矩阵说五千
if you have a matrix a say five thousand
一万个为什么是错误的
by ten thousand why is it a mistake to
实际上使用转置a
actually use a transpose a in the
计算我们用它很大
computation we used it big
大量的证据，我们可以找到
heavily in the proof and we could find
另一个不会使用它的证据
another proof that wouldn't use it so
很多，但为什么我不会为什么这样做
much but why would I not do why would I
不乘这两个在一起很
not multiply these two together it's
非常昂贵它增加了一个
very big very expensive it adds in a
你有一个矩阵
whole lot of roundoff you have a matrix
那是现在它的脆弱性
that's now it's vulnerability to
舍入误差是被调用的平方
roundoff errors is squared that's called
它的条件数得到平方
its condition number gets squared and
你只是不去那里实际
you just don't go there so the actual
计算方法相当
computational methods are quite
不同，我们会谈论那些但是
different and we'll talk about those but
a转置a因为它是
the the a transpose a because it's
对称正定的
symmetric positive-definite made the
证明很好，这就是你的意思
proof so nice that's that's what you've
看到最好的证据，我会说和
seen the nicest proof I'd say of the and
现在我应该考虑几何学
now I should think about the geometry so
什么是平等的
so what does a equal
一个你的sigmat也许我拿另一个
a well you sigmat maybe I take another
董事会，但它会填补它，但它是
board but it's it will fill it but it's
就像当你唱我的V置我这样
like when you sing my V transpose I so
它有三个因素，我愿意
it's got three factors there and I would
就像那时每个因素都是一种
like then each factor is kind of a
特殊矩阵U和V是正交的
special matrix U and V are orthogonal
矩阵所以我认为那些是旋转
matrix so I think of those as rotations
Sigma是我想到的对角矩阵
Sigma is a diagonal matrix I think of it
因为现在我正在努力
as stretching so now I'm just going to
绘制图片所以这里是单位向量
draw the picture so here's unit vectors
如果我是第一件事就是这样的话
and the first thing so this if I'm
乘以X这是第一件事
multiplied by X this is the first thing
这发生在这里旋转
that happens so that rotates here's
这是Xs然后VtransposeX就是这样
here's X s then V transpose X is that
那仍然是一个圆圈长度没有
that's still a circle length didn't
当我乘以一个时，改变那些
change for those when I multiply by an
正交矩阵，但矢量转向
orthogonal matrix but the vectors turned
轮换可能是一种反思
it's a rotation could be a reflection
但是让我们把它保持为现在轮换的东西
but let's keep it as a rotation now what
西格玛是否这样做我有这个单位圈
does Sigma do so I have this unit circle
这些我在2d所以我画了一张照片
these I'm in 2d so I'm drawing a picture
这些是向量的单位
of the vectors these are the unit
在2dXY的矢量他们被转向了
vectors in 2d X Y they got turned by the
正交矩阵
orthogonal matrix
西格玛对这张照片做了什么
what does Sigma do to that picture
它延伸，因为西格玛倍增
it stretches because Sigma multiplies by
Sigma1在第一组分Sigma2中
Sigma 1 in the first component Sigma 2
在第二个，所以它延伸这些家伙
in the second so it stretches these guys
并说让我们假设这是一个数
and say let's suppose this is number one
这是第二个数字
and this is number two this is number
一，这是第二
one and this is number two
所以Sigma我们的惯例是Sigmaone
so Sigma one our convention is Sigma one
我们总是把Sigma1等于更大
we always take Sigma 1 greater equals
西格玛2更大等于更大
Sigma 2 greater equal whatever greater
同等的西格玛排名和那个和那个
equal Sigma rank and that's and that
他们都很积极
they're all positive
其余的都是零，所以Sigma会的
and the rest are zero so Sigma one will
比西格玛二大，所以我
be bigger than Sigma two so I'm
期待这个椭圆它会改变
expecting this ellipse it'll change
圈定为椭圆，当你
circle goes to an ellipse when you
舒展我没有得到它相当
stretch the I didn't get it quite
完美但不坏，所以这就是这个
perfect but not bad so this was this
将是Sigma2V2VSigma1V1和
would be Sigma 2 V 2 V Sigma 1 V 1 and
这将是Sigma2V2，我们现在
this would be Sigma 2 V 2 and we now
有一个椭圆，所以我们从X开始
have an ellipse so we started with X's
在一个圆圈中，我们旋转，我们伸展和
in a circle we rotated we stretched and
现在最后一步是采取这些家伙
now the final step is take these guys
并将它们乘以你所以这就是
and multiply them by you so this was the
SigmaV转换X，现在我已经准备好了
Sigma V transpose X and now I'm ready
因为最后来的U部分
for the U part which comes last because
它在左边，发生了什么
it's at the left and what happens from
现在是什么画面你做了什么
what's the picture now what does you do
椭圆旋转它
to the ellipse it rotates it
它的另一个正交矩阵它
it's another orthogonal matrix it
将它旋转到可能存在的地方
rotates it somewhere maybe there and now
我们看到使用u2和u1做啊也许
we see the use u2 and u1 do ah maybe
也许他们在那里也许我让我放过
maybe they're there maybe I let me let
我认为基本上不是这样
me think about that basically that's not
那就对了
that's right
所以这个SVD告诉我们一些事情
so so this SVD is telling us something
每个线性都非常引人注目
quite remarkable that every linear
转换每个矩阵
transformation every matrix
乘法因子变为旋转
multiplication factors into a rotation
拉伸时间不同的时间
times a stretch times a different
旋转，但实际上可能不同
rotation but possibly different actually
你什么时候和V一样
when would the u be the same as the V
这是一个很好的问题，什么时候是你的
here's a good question when is U the
当两个单数时，与V相同
same as V when are the two singular
向量只是
vectors just
同样的，因为必须是
the same because a would have to be
广场，我们希望这是相同的
square and we want this to be the same
如果他们是QlambdaQ转置
as Q lambda Q transpose if they're the
同样如此使用将是相同的
same so the use would be the same as the
当矩阵是对称的时，V是
V's when the matrix is symmetric and
实际上我们需要它是积极的
actually we need it to be positive
明确的原因是因为我们的
definite why is that because our
惯例是这些家伙更大
convention is these guys are greater
如果这样的话，这些家伙就等于零
equal zero these guys if it's going to
是一样的然后是积极的
be the same then so for a positive
确定对称矩阵的S
definite symmetric matrix the the S the
我们开始的S与之相同
S that we started with is the same as
你是下一行的a耶
the you as the a on the next line yeah
Q是U的Q转置为V
the Q is the U the Q transpose as the V
转置lambda是Sigma所以
transpose the lambda is the Sigma so
那些是好的矩阵，它们是
those are the good matrices and they're
那些你无法改进的
the ones that you can't improve
基本上他们真好，你能
basically they're so good you can you
不能使正定对称
can't make a positive definite symmetric
矩阵比它更好
matrix better than it is
好吧也许对角化它或什么的
well maybe diagonalize it or something
但好吧，现在我想起了一个
but okay now I think of like one
在这里提问，它有助于帮助我
question here that it helps to helps me
无论如何要保持这个数字如何
anyway to keep this figure straight how
我想计算一下这里的参数
I want to count the parameters in this
因素分解，所以我是两个两个
factorization so I'm two by two
我是两个两个，所以一个有四个数字
I'm two by two so a has four numbers
ABCD然后我想我觉得那四个
ABCD then I guess I feel that four
数字应出现在右侧
numbers should appear on the right-hand
侧以某种方式在U和西格玛和
side somehow the U and the Sigma and the
V转置应该总共消耗掉
V transpose should use up a total of
四个数字所以我们有一个美丽的小镇
four numbers so we have a beautiful town
婷左边那间匹配
ting match between the left side that's
有四个数字abcd和右边
got four numbers a b c d and the right
这方面有
side that's got
数字埋在那里的某个地方
number is buried in there somewhere so
我们可以把它们挖出来吗？
can we dig them out how many numbers in
西格玛对Sigma1和Sigma非常清楚
Sigma that's pretty clear to Sigma 1 and
Sigma2的两个特征值有多少
Sigma 2 the two eigenvalues how many
这个轮换中的数字，所以如果我有一个
numbers in this rotation so I if I had a
不同颜色的粉笔我会放两个
different color chalk I would put two
因为我数了四件事
for the number of things I counted four
通过Sigma有两个参数
by Sigma how many parameters does a two
通过两次旋转需要1和什么是a
by two rotation require 1 and what's a
什么是那个或那个好词
what's a good word for that one or that
一个参数就像我有Rcos
one parameter it's like I have R cos
thetasinetheta减去sinethetacos
theta sine theta minus sine theta cos
theta有一个数字
theta there's a number
fada它是旋转的角度
fada it's it's the angle that rotates so
这是一个告诉轮换的人
that's one guy to tell the rotation
角度两个家伙告诉弹力
angle two guys to tell the stretchings
还有一个告诉轮换
and one more to tell the rotation from
你将最多四个这样所以那些
you adding up to four so so those
那些与四个匹配的帐户
account those match up with the four
号码我们开始的ABCD
numbers ABCD that we start with of
当然这是一个复杂的关系
course it's a complicated relation
在这四个数字和之间
between those four numbers and and
旋转和伸展，但它是
rotations and stretches but but it's
无论如何四等于四，我想如果
four equals four anyway and I guess if
你做了三个三个人，三个人
you did three by threes oh three by
三分之后会发生什么事情
threes what would happened then so let
我带三个你想要照顾
me take three do you want to care for
三个三分之一就是这样
three by threes just it's sort of
满足获得四个相等的4个，也
satisfying to get four equal four but
现在我们得到了三到三个
now what do we get three by three we got
这里有九个你好这么多数字
how many numbers here nine hello so
这九个数字在哪里如何
where are those nine numbers well how
这里很多人通常都很容易
many here that's usually the easy three
那么你的客人有多少人
so what's your guests for the how many
你需要旋转三维旋转
and a rotation in a 3d rotation you take
一个球体，你旋转它多少
a sphere and you rotate it how many how
许多数字告诉你什么是什么
many numbers to tell you what's what to
告诉你你做了什么，我们希望
tell you what you did three we hope
三，是的，它将是三三和
three yeah it's gonna be three three and
三为...为
three for the for the for the
我们生活的三维世界
three-dimensional world that we live in
所以以旋转为生的人
so people who do rotations for a living
明白在3d中旋转但如何
understand that a rotation in 3d but how
你看到了吗我的意思是三个字
do you see this I mean it's three words
我们做对了没关系，是的滚动
and we've got it right okay yeah roll
俯卧和偏航是的，我猜飞行员
pitch and yaw yeah I guess about pilot
希望知道那三个是啊
hopefully knows about those three yeah
是的，是的，当这些是滚动时
yeah yeah which is roll when these are
喜欢向前和向后哦哦，你在一个
like forward and back oh yo you're in a
你呆在飞机上，没关系
you stay in a plane and you okay
美丽的右边，这导致我们
beautiful right right and that leads us
以我们的四个四个维度什么是你的
to our four four dimensions what's your
在4d猜测
guess on 4d
好吧，我们可以再次计算
well let's we could do the count again
如果它是四乘四我们会有
if it was four by four we would have
十六个数字在那里和中间
sixteen numbers there and in the middle
我们总是有一个轻松的时间
we always have a easy time with that
那将是四个所以我们剩下12个
that would be four so we got 12 left to
分享出来，所以6个莫名其妙六六角度
share out so six somehow six six angles
在四个方面，我们留下它
in four dimensions well we leave it
在那里，是的，是的，好的，好吧
there yeah yeah yeah okay okay so
有SVD但没有例子
there's the SVD but without an example
你知道我必须要做的例子
examples you know I would have to
计算一个转置a并找到它
compute a transpose a and find it so the
文本将这样做会为一
text will do that does it for a
特别是矩阵哦
particular matrix Oh
是的，文本是为矩阵做的
yeah the text does it for a for a matrix
三四零五出来了
three four zero five that came out
很好啊，我们可以做的一些事实
pretty well uh a few facts we could
尽管如此，如果我倍增所有
learn though so the if I multiply all
特征值一起然后我一个
the eigenvalues together then I for a
矩阵A我会得到什么，我得到了
matrix a what do I get I get the
行列式
determinant
如果我乘以奇异值怎么办？
what if I multiply the singular values
一起
together
再一次，我得到了你能做到的决定因素
well again I get the determinant you can
看到它的大公式马上
see it right away from the big formula
把决定因素当作决定因素
take determinant take determinants well
假设矩阵a是正方形，那么它就是
assuming the matrix a is square so it's
有一个决定因素，然后我采取
got a determinant then I take
决定因素的决定因素
determinants the determinant of this
产品我可以分开
product I can take the separate
具有决定因素的决定因素
determinants that has determinant equal
一个正交矩阵
to one an orthogonal matrix the the the
行列式是1，类似于此
determinant is 1 and similarly here so
所以Sigma的产品也是
so the product of the Sigma's is also
决定因素是啊是的所以产品
the determinant yeah yeah so the product
Sigma的定义也是确定的
of the Sigma's is also the determinate
西格玛的产品将在这里
the product of the Sigma's here will be
15但你会发现Sigma1是
15 but you'll find that Sigma 1 is
小于lambda1所以这里是
smaller than lambda 1 so here are the
特征值lambda1小于等于
eigen values lambda 1 lesser equal
lambda2说但是奇异的价值观
lambda 2 say but but the singular values
在他们之外是的，但他们仍然
are outside them yeah but they still
将Sigma1乘以Sigma2
multiply Sigma 1 thing times Sigma 2
仍然是15，那是相同的
will still be 15 and that's the same as
lambda1次lambda2yep但总体而言
lambda 1 times lambda 2 yep but overall
计算SVD的例子
computing the examples of the of the SVD
花更多的时间，因为你是的
take more time because well yeah you
只计算一个转置a和你
just compute a transpose a and you've
得到了V，你就在路上
got the V's and you're on your way and
你必须采取平方根
you have to take the square roots of the
参数使得SVD成为一个
argument so that's the SVD as a
一块纯数学但当然是什么
piece of pure math but of course what
我们会做下一次启动的时候了
we'll do next time starting right away
正在使用SVD，让我告诉你，即使
is use SVD and let me tell you even
今天最重要的是，是的，最重要的
today the most yeah yeah most important
SVD的各个部分，我的意思是什么
pieces of the SVD so what do I mean by
SVD的各个部分我还有一个
pieces of the SVD I've got one more
黑板仍然是正确的，所以我们在这里
blackboard still the right on so here we
走
go
所以让我写出一个是你的用途
so let me write out a is you the use
西格玛Σ的1倍到R倍
times the Sigma's Sigma's 1 to R times
B的V转置V1向下移调
the B's V transpose V 1 transpose down
到VR转置所以那些是跨越的
to V R transpose so those are across
是的，实际上我在这里写的是这样的
yeah actually what I've written here so
那里你可以说有一个大的
there you could say there's a large big
经济有一个较小的经济体
economies there's a there's a smaller
尺寸SVD，有真正的东西
size SVD that has the real stuff that
真的很重要，然后有更大的
really counts and then there's a larger
SVD有很多零如此
SVD that has a whole lot of zeroes so so
这将是较小的一个M乘R或
this would be the smaller one M by R or
这将是RbyR，这些都是
this would be R by R and these would all
是积极的，这将是Rbynso
be positive and this would be R by n so
那是唯一使用的是非
that's the that's only using the are non
所有这些人都大于零
zeros all these guys are greater than
零，然后我们可以填补另一个
zero then the other one we could fill
得到正方形正交矩阵
out to get square orthogonal matrix the
Sigma和V的V1转换为
Sigma's and square V's V 1 transpose to
是和转置所以形状是什么
be and transpose so what are the shapes
现在这个形状是MbyM它是合适的
now this shape is M by M it's a proper
正交矩阵这个也是n乘n
orthogonal matrix this one also n by n
所以这家伙是这是适马
so this guy has to be this is the Sigma
现在所以它必须是什么
now so it has to be what
叹息M由n表示剩下的空间
sighs M by n that's the remaining space
所以它从Sigma的开始
so it starts with the Sigma's
然后这一切都为零占
and then it's all zeros accounting for
nullspacestuff是的你应该这样做
null space stuff yeah so you should
真的看到这两个是可能的
really see that these two are possible
当你这一切都是零
that that all these zeros when you
多出来就是什么都没有
multiply out just give nothing so that
真的是非零的唯一的东西
really the only thing that non zero is
在这些位中，但有一个完整的
in these bits but there's a complete one
那么这些额外的用途是什么呢？
so what are these extra use they're in
转置的零空间a
the null space of a transpose a
转置或转置是的两个
transpose or a transpose a yeah so two
尺寸大尺寸和小尺寸
sizes the large size and the small size
但他们就是重要的事情
but they're then the things that count
都在那里好，所以我要去
are all in there okay so I was going to
做一件事，我让我看看
do one more thing and I'm let me see
这是什么，所以这是
what what it was there so this is
你会看到说明的第1.8节
section 1.8 of the notes and you'll see
那里的例子，你会看到第二个
examples there and you'll see a second
找到叶子和B的方法
approach to the finding leaves and B's
和Sigma我可以告诉你那是什么
and Sigma's I can tell you what that is
但也许只有两个只是做
but maybe with just two just to do
最后一件好事告诉我
something nice at the end let me tell
你关于a的另一个因素分解
you about another factorization of a
这是着名的着名的
that was famous that's famous in
工程，它在中国很有名
engineering and it's famous in in
几何，所以这是一个你的西格玛V
geometry so this is any a as a u Sigma V
转置我们现在已经有了
transpose we've got that now the the the
我正在考虑的另一个我会说的
other one that I'm thinking of I'll tell
你的名字，它被称为极点
you its name it's called the pole
矩阵的分解和我想要的一切
decomposition of a matrix and all I want
你要看到它是虚拟的
you to see is that it's it's virtually
在这里，极地意味着什么是极地和
here so a polar means what's polar and
对于复数，什么是极性形式
for complex number what's the polar form
一个复杂的数字真正的家伙
of a complex number a real guy
所以真正的家伙R将翻译成一个
so the real guy R will translate into a
对称的家伙和我对thethethethe
symmetric guy and the e to the I theta
将翻译成他所说的话
will translate into so what does he say
什么样的矩阵让你想起e
what kind of a matrix reminds you of e
在我THETA还是遗憾尺寸之一，所以
to the I theta or sorry size one so
正交所以这是一个非常非常使用
orthogonal so that's a very using very
各种矩阵因素都很好
kind of nice every matrix factors into
对称矩阵乘以正交
symmetric matrix times an orthogonal
矩阵和我当然将这些描述为
matrix and I of course describe these as
最重要的矩阵类
the most important classes of matrices
在这里我们说每个矩阵都是一个
and here we're saying every matrix is a
s次aq我也说我
s times aq and I'm also saying that I
可以迅速摆脱出局
can get that quickly out of out of the
SVD所以我只想这样做，所以我想要
SVD so I'm just want to do it so I want
找到一个S并找到一个这样的Q.
to find an S and find a Q out of this so
得到一个S所以让我开始吧
to get an S so let me just start it you
西格玛，但现在我正在寻找一个S.
Sigma but now I'm looking for an S so
我现在该怎么做呢
what shall I take put in now
我把一个更好的投入，如果我有你
I put a better put in if I've got you
西格玛的东西，我想要它
Sigma something and I want it to be
对称我不应该放在你身上
symmetric I shouldn't put in you
转置会做，但如果我放
transpose will do it but then if I put
在你的转调我必须把你这么做
in u transpose I've got to put in you so
现在我有你的Sigmau转置U是
now I've got you Sigma u transpose U is
现在的身份我必须得到V.
the identity now I've got to get V
转置，我得到了极地
transpose and have I got what the polar
在这一行中要求分解
decomposition is asking for in this line
所以是的，我觉得我在这里得到了什么
so yeah I think what do I got here
哪里是S的地方，所以这样
where's the where's the S and this so
你看我接受了SVD而我只是放了
you see I took the SVD and I just put
那里的身份刚刚转移
the identity in there just shifted
事情有点现在在哪里
things a little and now where's the s
我可以直接读一读
that I can read off for a straight
这是一个对称矩阵的S.
that's an S that's a symmetric matrix
Q我认为我们可以在哪里
and where's the Q well I guess we can
看看Q必须在哪里，是的
see where the Q has to be it's here yeah
是的，只要坚持你转移你
yeah so just by sticking u transpose U
并查找和括起括号
and looking and putting the parentheses
对，我恢复那个分解
right what I recover that decomposition
在机械中的矩阵
of a matrix which in in mechanical
工程语言语言告诉我
engineering languages language tells me
任何一个应变都可以让你知道哪个
that any strain can be you know which is
喜欢拉伸弹性的东西
like stretching of a of elastic thing
有一种对称的伸展
has a has a symmetric kind of a stretch
和内部扭曲是的，所以这是好的
and internal twist yeah so that's good
那么这很多是三六九
well this was a lot of three six nine
它充满了矩阵
boards filled with matrices well it is
1806五，所以也许没关系
1806 five so maybe that's all right but
我们的想法是在矩阵上使用它们
the idea is to use them on a matrix of
数据和
data and
我只会告诉你钥匙的关键事实
I'll just tell you the key fact the key
事实上，如果我有一个很大的数据矩阵嘿
fact if I have a big matrix of data Hey
如果我想退出那个矩阵
and if I want to pull out of that matrix
这个重要的部分是什么数据
the important part so that's what data
科学必须做大做事
science has to be doing out of a big
矩阵中的一部分是其中的一部分
matrix some of those some part of it is
噪音的一部分是信号我
noise some part of it is signal I'm
寻找最重要的部分
looking for the most important part of
这里的信号，所以我在寻找
the signal here so I'm looking for the
a中矩阵最重要的部分
most important part of the matrix in a
最大的数字，但是那个和那个
way the biggest numbers but but that and
我当然看看个别数字
of course I'm look at individual numbers
那么矩阵中最重要的部分是什么
so what's the biggest part of the matrix
什么是校长
what's the what are the principal
组件现在我们真的进入了
components now we're really getting in
如果这是一个如果你知道它可以
if this is a if this you know it could
是数据，我们想做统计数据
be data and we want to do statistics so
我们希望看到什么是高点
we want to see what's what has high
方差我们的方差很小
variance what has low variance we'll
我们将与之建立联系
we'll do these connections with
统计数据，但重要的是什么
statistics but what's the important part
矩阵井的意思是看
of the matrix well that means look at
在你西格玛V移调这里啊，让
the you Sigma V transpose here yeah let
我看看有啥一个最
me look at it so what's the one most
该矩阵的重要组成部分
important part of that of that matrix
一个是正​​确的，它是一个等级P所以
one the right one it's a rank one P so
当我说一部分时，我当然是
when I say a part I'm of course it's
将成为一个矩阵部分，但所以
going to be a matrix part but so the
简单的矩阵构建块就像一个
simple matrix building block is like a
排名一个矩阵什么东西
rank one matrix something something
调换，我应该拉出来
transpose and what should I pull out of
这是最重要的排名
that as being the most important rank
这个产品就是一个矩阵
one matrix that's in that product so
在你的时候我会把它擦掉一点八
I'll erase it one point eight while you
想想我该怎么做
think what do I do
把事情搞清楚了
to pick out the big deal the the thing
数据首先告诉我
that the data is telling me first well
这些是
these are
在正常的北方我不能没有人更大
north of normal I can no one is bigger
这些都是正交的
than another one these are orthonormal
没有人比另一个更大但是
no one is bigger than another one but
我在这里看看哪个是最多的
here I look here which is the most
重要数字Sigma1Sigma1所以
important number Sigma 1 Sigma 1 so the
我挑选的部分是这个最大的数字
part I pick out is this biggest number
它的Rho倍于它的列，所以它就是你
times its Rho times its column so it's u
1Sigma1V1转置是顶部
1 Sigma 1 V 1 transpose is the the top
矩阵的主要部分是它
principal part of the matrix a it's the
矩阵的前导部分是它的
leading part of the matrix a it's the
排名第一的是最大排名的一部分
rank one the biggest rank one part of
矩阵在那里计算那些
the matrix is there so computing those
三个家伙是迈出的第一步
three guys is the first step to
了解数据是的，所以
understanding the data yeah so that's
接下来会发生什么，我猜
what's coming next is and I guess
明天，因为他们周一搬了我的
tomorrow since they moved Monday my
教会周二宣布为星期一
teach declared Tuesday to be Monday
他们周三没有改变
there they didn't change Wednesday so
I'll see you tomorrow for the the
我会看到你明天的中
主要成分
principal components